Guide to the Robert Watts Hudgens Papers, 1925-1973 RL.00584
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert Watts Hudgens papers
1925-1973
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hudgens, Robert Watts, 1896-1973
RL.00584
12 Linear Feet
Robert Watts "Pete" Hudgens (1896-1973), an investment banker, government official, corporation executive and amateur printer, was born in Laurens County, South Carolina. Personal and professional correspondence, writings, speeches, topical publications and notes, and other papers, relating to rural development programs in the U.S. and other countries, especially Latin America, U.S. Farmers Home Administration, Chapel Hill, N.C., The Citadel, Cosmos Club, Faith at Work, International Development Services, Society for International Development, Southeast Public Health Foundation, National Sharecroppers Fund, National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor, and Latin America.
6,400 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Papers of Robert Watts Hudgens were acquired by Duke University in 1978.
Biographical Note
Robert Watts Pete Hudgens (1896-1973), an investment banker, government official, corporation executive and amateur printer, was born in Laurens County, South Carolina. He graduated from the Citadel in 1915. He served to the rank of captain in the U.S. Army in World War I, was severely wounded in 1918, and spent three years in hospitals before being discharged in 1921. He then became an investment banker, a partner in the firm of Alester G. Furman, his father-in-law, in Greenville, S.C. During his years with the firm (1921-1934) he was also an official of the Greenville Chapter of the American Red Cross and the South Carolina Red Cross, and in these capacities he became involved with the relief of farmers who were suffering economic hardship in the state. To help them he developed a program known as supervised credit, which combined credit with technical assistance. Supervised credit was first used, successfully, in Abbeville County, S.C. (1932-1933), with the assistance of a grant from the American Red Cross, and eventually became the basis of programs used by the Resettlement Administration and the Farm Security Administration. Hudgens' success in rural development led to his 14 years of service in government organizations: the Subsistence Homestead program (1934-1935); the Resettlement Administration, as Louisiana State Director (1935-1936) and as regional director for the Southeast (1936-1937); and the Farm Security Administration, as regional director for the Southeast, and as assistant and then associate, director of the administration (1937-1946).
Hudgens left government service in 1946 and worked a year as director of field organizations for the American Red Cross (1946-1947). He then became executive director of Nelson Rockefeller's American International Association for Economic and Social Development (1948-1953), where he was able to work with rural development programs in other countries, especially in Latin America.
These same concepts were carried over to International Development Services, Inc., which Hudgens formed in 1953. He served as its president until his retirement to Chapel Hill, N.C., in 1963.
Collection Overview
The collection primarily concerns Hudgens' activities after 1949, and consists of correspondence, printed materials, personal and organizational papers, many of Hudgens' writings, topical publications and notes, and other miscellaneous papers. Excellent coverage of the pre-l950 period is found in The Reminiscences of Robert W. Hudgens, microfiche no. 95 of Part II of the Columbia Oral History Collection, available in the Newspapers and Microforms Department.
Hudgens' continuing interest and involvement in the field of economic development at home and abroad is reflected in the files for the Farmers Home Administration (1938-1972), International Development Services (1956-1971), the American International Association (1948-1972), Agricultural Workers (1952-1971), the Society for International Development (1959-1972), the International Study and Research Institute (1963-1970), the National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor (1958-1968), the National Sharecroppers Fund (1962-1972), the National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor (1951-1967), and in files for individuals that shared his concerns and interest in the subject, such as Will Winton Alexander, Paul Henson Appleby, Hubert Horatio Humphrey, Luigi Gino Ligutti, Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller, Paul Schuster Taylor, and James Gray Maddox. There are files for the Delmo Housing Corporation and Gee's Bend, Alabama, which were cooperative projects that confronted Depression-era problems.
Hudgens was actively involved in religious organizations and in churches. He was president of the board of directors of Faith At Work, and the file for this organization covers the years 1951-1972. There are also files for the Riverside Church, New York (1956-1971) and the United Church of Christ in Chapel Hill, N.C. (1958-1973).
Hudgens' involvement in a number of state and local groups after his retirement to Chapel Hill is shown in such files as those for the Chapel Hill Historical Society (1967-1972), the Men's Garden Club of Chapel Hill (1963-1970), Friends of the Chapel Hill Public Library (1967-1972), and the North Carolina Council on World Affairs.
Hudgens was an active, and often welcome, speaker and writer on current events and on the lessons he learned in dealing with economic development and rural problems, and several files contain examples of his notes, speeches and writings. For example, he was Regents Lecturer at the University of California at Berkeley (1955), and was a guest lecturer at The Citadel (1963-1967), Syracuse University (Paul H. Appleby File, 1949-1954) and Columbia University (1954-1955). He was a participant in the Ray Kaighn Conversation Group in Chapel Hill. He was also proprietor of the Rooster Press of Chapel Hill whose publications were Hudgens' essays and editorials on current events and Southern culture, many of which were reprinted in several North Carolina newspapers, as well as miscellaneous cards, calendars, announcements, etc.
Other significant files include the Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C. (1946-1972); the Southeast Public Health Foundation (1965-1972), which he helped to found; and those of many acquaintances of note. There are several files dealing directly with Hudgens and his works (Biographical, Financial, Miscellaneous Writings and Rooster Press), as well as correspondence with numerous of his relatives.
Organization Note
When the collection was received it was arranged in separate folders for individuals, families, organizations and topics, and in an alphabetical series of folders containing materials on the same range of subjects. The collection has been reorganized into separate individual, family, organization and topical files, alphabetically arranged. A list of files follows below.
Latin America -- Economic conditions; Chapel Hill (N.C.) -- Economic development; Rural development -- Latin America; Rural development -- International cooperation; Rural development -- United States; Society for International Development; Southeast Public Health Foundation; United States. Farmers Home Administration; Hudgens, Robert Watts, 1896-1973; Cosmos Club (Washington, D.C.); International Development Services; Faith at Work (Organization); National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor; National Sharecroppers' Fund (U.S.); Citadel Academy (Charleston, S.C.)
- Robert Watts Hudgens Papers, 1925-1973, 25 boxes
  - Adams, Judith: 1963 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Development Council: 1963-1972 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Workers: 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural Workers: 1962-1971 (Box 1)
  - Aguirre Tupper, Fernando: 1963-1971 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Will Winton: 1948-1972 (Box 1)
  - Alliance for Progress: 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society: 1947-1958 (Box 1)
  - American International Association: 1948-1972 (Box 2)
  - American Legion: 1946-1951 (Box 2)
  - American Red Cross: 1952-1957 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Democratic Action: 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - Ames, Jessie (Daniel): 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, James: 1964 (Box 3)
  - Andrews, Stanley: 1952 (Box 3)
  - Anonymous (A poem, possibly by Robert W. Hudgens): 1925 (Box 3)
  - Appleby, Paul Henson: 1947-1951 (Box 3)
  - Appleby, Paul Henson: 1952-1964 (Box 3)
  - Arnold, Edwin Gustaf: 1952-1954 (Box 3)
  - Arnold Family (Family of Walter Harold Arnold, brother-in-law of Eleanor Furman Hudgens): 1948-1971 (Box 3)
  - Ascoli, Max: 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Atcon, Rudolf P.: 1961 (Box 3)
  - Atwater, Reginald Meyers: 1955 (Box 3)
  - Avery, Virginia: 1970 (Box 3)
  - Bagley, Henry W.: 1958-1961 (Box 3)
  - Bailey, Charles P.: 1959 (Box 3)
  - Bailey Family (Family of Broadus Bailey, brother-in-law of Eleanor Furman Hudgens): 1953-1972 (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, Calvin B.: 1953 (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, Sidney: 1961-1968 (Box 3)
  - Barnes, George Anthony: 1958 (Box 3)
  - Barr, Stringfellow: 1953-1972 (Box 3)
  - Beach, Robert Fullerton: 1958 (Box 3)
  - Beecher, John: 1948-1972 (Box 3)
  - Beecher, John and Barbara: Works: 1940-1964 (Box 3)
  - Benedict, Murray Reed: 1947 (Box 3)
  - Bertsch, Howard: 1958-1967 (Box 3)
  - Bissell, Titus C.: 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Blackwell, Gordon Williams: 1960-1972 (Box 3)
  - Though, Ray: 1958-1961 (Box 3)
  - Boek, Walter Erwin: 1962-1972 (Box 3)
  - Bondy, Robert Earl: 1964 (Box 3)
  - Borella, Victor: 1954 (Box 3)
  - Brandenburg, Earl W.: 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brannan, Charles Franklin: 1960-1965 (Box 4)
  - Bristol, Lee Hastings: 1959-1962 (Box 4)
  - Brooks, Lee Marshall: 1966-1972 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Philip Marshall: 1947-1960 (Box 4)
  - Buchanan, Archibald C.: 1960 (Box 4)
  - Buckner, George Walker: 1964-1970 (Box 4)
  - Byrnes, James Francis: 1953 (Box 4)
  - Cabaniss, Edward M.: 1960 (Box 4)
  - Cardon, Philip Vincent: 1949 (Box 4)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions: 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - Chapel Hill Gravel: 1965-1970 (Box 4)
  - Chapel Hill Historical Society: 1967-1972 (Box 4)
  - Chavez, Dennis: 1954 (Box 4)
  - Childs, Marquis William: 1954-1964 (Box 4)
  - The Citadel: 1942-1953 (Box 4)
  - The Citadel: 1954-1961 (Box 4)
  - The Citadel: Commencement:1967 (Box 4)
  - The Citadel: Summer Institute: 1963-1967 (Box 4)
  - The Citadel Development Foundation: 1963-1969 (Box 4)
  - Clark, Pearl F.: 1955 (Box 4)
  - Clawson, Marion: 1964-1967 (Box 4)
  - Cleveland, James Harlan: 1954-1970 (Box 4)
  - Cole, Lawrence Edward: 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Coleman, Henry Crim: 1963 (Box 5)
  - Columbia University Oral History Project: 1972 (Box 5)
  - Columbia University Seminar: 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - Columbia University Seminar: 1956-1962 (Box 5)
  - Common Cause: 1955-1972 (Box 5)
  - Conway Family (John and Francis Conway, possible relatives of Robert W. Hudgens): 1953-1970 (Box 5)
  - Copeland, James Issac: 1969 (Box 5)
  - Cart, William Walter: 1967 (Box 5)
  - Cory, William Johnson: undated (Box 5)
  - Cosmos Club: 1946-1962 (Box 6)
  - Cosmos Club: 1963-1965 (Box 6)
  - Cosmos Club: 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Cosmos Club: 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Cosmos Club: 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Cosmos Club Bulletin: 1953-1973 (Box 6)
  - Couch, Virgil Lee: 1961 (Box 6)
  - Cousins, Norman: 1953-1972 (Box 6)
  - Cowen, Wilson: 1964-1967 (Box 6)
  - Cruishank, Nelson Hale: 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Curran Family (Frank J. and Charlotte Curran): 1967 (Box 6)
  - Daniel, Charles Ezra: 1954 (Box 6)
  - Davis, Ray E.: 1950 (Box 6)
  - Deane, Charles Bennett: 1952 (Box 6)
  - Delmo Homes: 1965-1968 (Box 6)
  - Democratic Party: 1960-1972 (Box 6)
  - Derieux, James Clarkson: 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Development and Resources Corporation: 1965 (Box 6)
  - Dickinson, Raymond L.: 1958 (Box 6)
  - Disabled Officers Association: 1958-1971 (Box 6)
  - Dobyns, Henry Farmer: 1963-1966 (Box 6)
  - Dolan, Margaret Baggett: 1968-1972 (Box 6)
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan: 1945-1965 (Box 6)
  - Duncan, John C.: 1966 (Box 6)
  - Dunlap, Annie (Hudgens) (Aunt of Robert W. Hudgens): 1944-1948 (Box 6)
  - Dykes, Jefferson Chenowth: 1958 (Box 6)
  - Edgell, Alvin G.: 1963-1971 (Box 6)
  - Eisenhower, Milton Stover: July 20 (Box 6)
  - Ethridge Family (Mark Foster and Willie Snow Ethridge): 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Evans Family (William Ney and May Thompson Evans): 1950-1972 (Box 6)
  - Ewing, Oscar Ross: 1972 (Box 6)
  - Faith at Work: 1951-May, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Faith at Work: June, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Faith at Work: 1962 (Box 7)
  - Faith at Work: 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Faith at Work: 1965-1967 (Box 7)
  - Faith at Work: 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Fink, Arthur Emil: Jan. 20 (Box 8)
  - Fischer. John: 1946-1973 (Box 8)
  - Fischer, Joseph Lyman: 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Fletcher Family (Arthur and Vivian Fletcher): 1966-1967 (Box 8)
  - Fountain, Lawrence H.: 1971 (Box 8)
  - Frank, Jerome David: 1964 (Box 8)
  - Friends of the Chapel Hill Public Library: 1967-1972 (Box 8)
  - Fryer Family (E. Reeseman, lone and Sue Elleanore Fryer): 1957-1969 (Box 8)
  - Fuller (Benjamin) Family (Family of Benjamin Rutledge Fuller, stepfather of Robert W. Hudgens): 1947-1971 (Box 8)
  - Fuller (John) Family (Family of John D. Fuller, possibly related to Robert W. Hudgens): 1954-1972 (Box 8)
  - Fullilove, Sam: 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Furman Family (Families of Alester Garden Furman, Jr., brother of Eleanor Furman Hudgens, and of his son, Alester Garden Furman III): 1946-1955 (Box 8)
  - Furman Family: 1956-1972 (Box 8)
  - Gaer, Joseph: 1949-1959 (Box 8)
  - Gardening: 1964-1972 (Box 8)
  - Garst, Robert: 1966 (Box 8)
  - Gates, Thomas Sovereign: 1958 (Box 8)
  - Gee's Bend: 1947-1969 (Box 8)
  - Giesecke, Albert Anthony: 1952 (Box 8)
  - Gil, Frederico Guillermo: 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - Glick, Philip Milton: 1955-1972 (Box 8)
  - Gobbel, James Thomas: 1947 (Box 8)
  - Goldschmidt, Arthur Edward: 1949-1972 (Box 8)
  - Goldsmith, Margaret: 1960 (Box 8)
  - Gomez Garcia, Anibal: 1967-1972 (Box 9)
  - Goncalves de Souza, Joso: 1958 (Box 9)
  - Graham, Frank Porter: 1963-1972 (Box 9)
  - Graves, Louis: 1963-1968 (Box 9)
  - Griffing, John B. 1958-1962 (Box 9)
  - Grisham Family (Glen and Olga Grisham): 1956-1968 (Box 9)
  - Grubbs, Donald Hughes: 1963 (Box 9)
  - Guess, Joe: 1949-1970 (Box 9)
  - Guess, Joe: 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Hall, Wilton Earle: 1947 (Box 9)
  - Hambidge, Gove: 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hammond, Edward Cuyler: 1968 (Box 9)
  - Hampden-Sydney College: 1960-1961 (Box 9)
  - Hanson, Haldore: 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Harkness, John C.: 1965-1972 (Box 9)
  - Harrison, James Leftwich: 1949 (Box 9)
  - Hawthorne, Hugh Robert: 1961 (Box 9)
  - Haynsworth, Clement Furman: 1964-1969 (Box 9)
  - Hays, Brooks: 1958-1972 (Box 9)
  - Heald, Kenneth Conrad: 1968 (Box 9)
  - Heilman, John: 1953-1962 (Box 9)
  - Helmreich, Ralph Louis: 1958 (Box 9)
  - Help for a Hungry World: 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Herz, Michael M.: 1964 (Box 9)
  - Hewes, Laurence Isley: 1946-1972 (Box 9)
  - Hickey, Vivian: 1965-1972 (Box 9)
  - Hicks, Frank Dewitt: 1967-1972 (Box 9)
  - Hill, Lister: 1946-1968 (Box 9)
  - Himebaugh, Keith: 1960-1971 (Box 10)
  - Himstead, Ralph Ebner: 1951-1956 (Box 10)
  - Hobbs, Samuel Huntington: 1969 (Box 10)
  - Hobby, William Pettus: 1959 (Box 10)
  - Hobson, Jessie Edward: 1964 (Box 10)
  - Hoffman, Anna M. (Rosenburg): 1949-1962 (Box 10)
  - Hoge, James Fulton: 1959-1963 (Box 10)
  - Hollings, Ernest Frank: 1969 (Box 10)
  - Howell, Almonte Charles: 1969-1971 (Box 10)
  - Hoyt, James Alfred: 1949-1965 (Box 10)
  - Hoyt, Winthrop: 1951-1972 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens, Eugene S. (Cousin of Robert W. Hudgens): 1960 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens, Lucia Taylor, Sr. (Relative of Robert W. Hudgens): 1965 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens, Lucia Taylor, Jr. (Relative of Robert W. Hudgens): 1949-1958 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens, Richard Watts (Son of Robert W. Hudgens): 1962-1968 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Addresses (Drafts and printed and typewritten copies of addresses made by Robert W. Hudgens): 1946-1961 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Addresses: 1963-1967 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Biographical (Includes various sketches, documents, records, clippings, pictures and other biographical papers concerning Robert W. Hudgens, and, to a limited degree, his wife, Eleanor Furman Hudgens): 1946-1952 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Biographical: 1963-1972 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Financial (Miscellaneous Financial papers of Robert W. Hudgens): 1953-1963 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Misc. Writings (Drafts, letters, articles, pamphlets, reports, etc. by Robert W. Hudgens): 1941-1964 (Box 10)
  - Hudgens' Misc. Writings: 1965-1972 (Box 10)
  - Hudgins Family: undated (Box 11)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio: 1952 (Box 11)
  - Inman, Samuel Guy: 1958-1962 (Box 11)
  - Institute for Religious and Social Studies: 1957-1960 (Box 11)
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development: 1961 (Box 11)
  - International Development Conference: 1966 (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1956-July, 1962 (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1962, Aug.-Dec. (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1963, Jan.-May (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1963, June-Sept. (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1963, Oct.-Dec. (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1964-1967 (Box 11)
  - International Development Services: 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - International Study and Research Institute: 1963-1970 (Box 11)
  - Jackson, N. Baxter: 1958 (Box 12)
  - Jackson Family (Gardner and Pat Jackson): 1952-1969 (Box 12)
  - Jamieson, William D.: 1948 (Box 12)
  - Jeffries, Elizabeth (Townsend) (Relative of Robert W. Hudgens): 1969 (Box 12)
  - Jervey Family (Family of James Wilkerson Jervey, whose daughter Alletta Wood Jervey, married Robert W. Hudgens' son, Richard Watts Hudgens): 1951-1968 (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Guy Benton: 1969 (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Shelby: 1971 (Box 12)
  - Johnson, Vernon Webster: 1967-1970 (Box 12)
  - Jones, Peter Smith: 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Kendall, Henry Plimpton: 1947-1948 (Box 12)
  - Kerr, Clark: 1957 (Box 12)
  - Keys, J.C.: 1947-1970 (Box 12)
  - Kilpatrick, Carroll: 1965 (Box 12)
  - Knapp, Joseph Grant: 1967-1971 (Box 12)
  - Kraft, John H.: 1958 (Box 12)
  - Land Reform, Peru: 1948-Sept., 1963 (Box 12)
  - Land Reform, Peru: 1963, Oct.-1969 (Box 12)
  - Land Tenure Center: 1963-1969 (Box 12)
  - Latin America: 1950-1961 (Box 13)
  - Latin America: 1962-1969 (Box 13)
  - Lawrence, David: 1965-1969 (Box 13)
  - Leagans, John Paul: 1967 (Box 13)
  - League for the American Home: 1948-1951 (Box 13)
  - LeCron, James D.: 1947-1949 (Box 13)
  - Lee, John F.: 1961-1965 (Box 13)
  - Legg, James: 1961 (Box 13)
  - LeTellier, Louis Shepherd: 1953 (Box 13)
  - Levin Family (Nathan and Pam Levin): 1962-1963 (Box 13)
  - Lewis Family (Family of Nellie Hoyt Lewis, daughter of Robert W. Hudgens, and her husband, Walter E. Lewis): 1965-1972 (Box 13)
  - Lewis, Burdette Gibson: 1952-1958 (Box 13)
  - Lewis, Henry Wilkins: 1963-1965 (Box 13)
  - Liebenow, Robert C.: 1961 (Box 13)
  - Lieberman, Jay Benjamin: 1960-1971 (Box 13)
  - Ligutti, Luigi Gino: 1952-1967 (Box 13)
  - Liss, Samuel: 1948-1953 (Box 13)
  - Lodwick, B.W.: 1958 (Box 13)
  - Loomis, Milton Early: 1968-1972 (Box 13)
  - McCall, Arthur Crosswell: 1951 (Box 14)
  - McCallister, Ralph: 1966-1972 (Box 14)
  - McCamy, James Lucian: 1948 (Box 14)
  - McCracken, Robert James: 1952-1962 (Box 14)
  - McDavid, Raven Ivor: 1951- 1964 (Box 14)
  - McGrail, Richard P.: 1948 (Box 14)
  - MacNeil, Robert B.: 1967 (Box 14)
  - Maddox, James Gray: 1955-1972 (Box 14)
  - Mahon, Gabriel Heywood: 1950-1964 (Box 14)
  - Malik, Charles Habib: 1954-1965 (Box 14)
  - Malone, Dumas: 1955-1972 (Box 14)
  - Manning, Wyndham Meredith: 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Maris Family (Family of Paul V. Marls): 1945-1972 (Box 14)
  - Marshall, Ralph Tannahill: 1963-1971 (Box 14)
  - Mayo Clinic: undated (Box 14)
  - Meares, Robert L.: 1964-1970 (Box 14)
  - Men's Garden Club of Chapel Hill: 1963-1970 (Box 14)
  - Merritt, Lewie Griffith: 1966-1967 (Box 14)
  - Minor, William Arthur: 1949 (Box 14)
  - Mitchell, George Sinclair: 1952-1958 (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, Harry Leland: 1957-1972 (Box 15)
  - Moore, John W.: 1958-1965 (Box 15)
  - Moore, Robert Murray: 1947 (Box 15)
  - Morgan, Arthur Ernest: 1964 (Box 15)
  - Mott, Frederick Dodge: 1947-1972 (Box 15)
  - Myers Family (Dewitt L. and Alic Myers): 1964-1972 (Box 15)
  - National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor: 1958-1963 (Box 15)
  - National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor: 1964-1968 (Box 15)
  - National Committee for Christian Leadership: 1947-1948 (Box 15)
  - National Consumers League: 1960-1971 (Box 15)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America: 1951-1970 (Box 15)
  - National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor: 1951-1967 (Box 15)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund: 1962-1965 (Box 16)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund: 1966-1968 (Box 16)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund: 1969-1972 (Box 16)
  - Neale, John R.: 1957-1958 (Box 16)
  - New York City Housing Authority: 1958 (Box 16)
  - New York Southern Society: 1949-1959 (Box 16)
  - Nicholson, Donald Lon: 1947 (Box 16)
  - North Carolina Council on World Affairs: 1963-1968 (Box 16)
  - North Carolina Fund: 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - North Carolina State Beekeepers Association: 1963 (Box 16)
  - Parisius, Herbert W.: 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Patton, Ernest: 1960-1961 (Box 16)
  - Patton, James George: 1948-1971 (Box 16)
  - Peace, Roger Craft: 1948 (Box 16)
  - Pearson, Drew Andrew Russell: 1953-1967 (Box 16)
  - Peet, Herbert M.: 1950-1959 (Box 16)
  - Perkins, Milo Randolph: 1948-1968 (Box 16)
  - Peterson, Lyall Ellis: 1958-1969 (Box 16)
  - Picard, Ralph Alan: 1952 (Box 16)
  - Pierce, John H.: 1947-1948 (Box 17)
  - Pohlmann, Kenneth E.: 1966-1969 (Box 17)
  - Pope, Thomas Harrington: 1952 (Box 17)
  - Poteat, Edwin McNeill: 1948-1950 (Box 17)
  - Powell, Oscar Morgan: 1956-1964 (Box 17)
  - Pratt, Henry Nickerson: 1947 (Box 17)
  - Radio Station WCFM: 1947 (Box 17)
  - Raper, Arthur Franklin: 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Ray Kaighn Conversation Group: 1962-1972 (Box 17)
  - Reed, Vergil D,: 1956-1966 (Box 17)
  - Reid, T. Roy: 1954-1968 (Box 17)
  - Reierson, Roy Lester: 1958 (Box 17)
  - Research Triangle: 1961-1971 (Box 17)
  - Retirement: 1966-1972 (Box 17)
  - Reuter, Richard Ward: 1962 (Box 17)
  - Rhoads, Cornelius Packard: 1953-1959 (Box 17)
  - Richards, James Prioleau: 1954-1957 (Box 17)
  - Richardson, Eudora Ramsay: 1963-1966 (Box 17)
  - Richmond Public Forum: 1965 (Box 17)
  - Riverside Church: 1956-1971 (Box 17)
  - Robert, Joseph Clark: 1937-1956 (Box 17)
  - Robert, Joseph Clark: 1957-1963 (Box 17)
  - Robert, Joseph Clark: 1964-1972 (Box 17)
  - Robertson Family (Family of Katherine Gary Robertson, half-sister of Robert W. Hudgens, and her husband, Alexander H. Robertson): 1950-1965 (Box 17)
  - Rockefeller, John Davison: 1960 (Box 18)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson Aldrich: 1948-1962 (Box 18)
  - Rockefeller Center Luncheon Club: 1947-1963 (Box 18)
  - Rogers, Gifford Eugene: 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Rohrbaugh, Lewis Henry: 1949-1973 (Box 18)
  - Rooster Press (Drafts and copies of Rooster Press publications, and miscellaneous papers): 1964-1966 (Box 18)
  - Rooster Press: 1967-1973 (Box 18)
  - Rooster Press Handouts: undated (Box 18)
  - Rosenthal Family (Family of Morris Rosenthal): 1954-1961 (Box 18)
  - Ross, Emory: 1956-1963 (Box 18)
  - Roth, Irving: 1968 (Box 18)